Joseph L. Rauh Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
- Part IV: Miscellany, 1940-1993 (Box 287-289)
  - Oral history projects
    - Fly, James Lawrence, Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 1971
    - Harry S. Truman Library, Independence, Mo., 1989
    - Lowenstein, Allard K., Columbia University, New York, N.Y., 1989
  - Speeches, 1967-1993, undated, (9 folders) (Box 289)
  - Writings
    - Articles, 1979-1992, undated, (3 folders)
    - Book, proposed, 1990, undated
    - Book reviews, 1940, 1983, undated
    - Miscellaneous, 1989, undated
- Part V: 2015 Addition, 1913-2008 (Box 290-299)
  Correspondence, memoranda, briefs and legal papers, interviews, reports, speeches and writings, photographs, family papers, newspaper clippings, and printed matter.
  - Correspondence, 1942-1943, 1960-1995, undated, (12 folders) (Box 290)
  - Legal file
    - Brotherhood of Locomotive Firemen and Enginemen, 1966-1969
    - Democratic National Convention of 1968, brief in support of the Georgia Delegation of Loyal National Democrats, 1968
    - Leadership Conference on Civil Rights, 1991
    - Maryland's system of school finance, report, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 291)
    - Miscellany of briefs, petitions, and opinions (arranged by client or case title)
      - A-B and G-H, 1961-1982, (3 folders)
      - I-K, R-U, and W-Y, circa 1958-1970, 1979, (3 folders) (Box 292)
    - Orlikow v. United States, 1991-1997
    - Remington, William Walter
      - Correspondence
        - General
          - 1950, (10 folders)
          - 1951
            - Jan.-May, (5 folders)
            - June-Dec., (9 folders) (Box 293)
          - 1952-1953, (19 folders)
          - 1954-1958, (4 folders) (Box 294)
        - “Hollywood” (movie prospects), 1949-1954, (4 folders)
        - Remington, William Walter, 1948-1953, (5 folders)
      - Newspaper clippings, 1949-1953, (9 folders)
      - Remington v. Bentley, 1948-1952, 1970, (11 folders) (Box 295)
      - Remington, Ann, 1949
      - United States v. Remington
        - Interviews and memoranda of conversations, 1950, (5 folders)
        - Legal memoranda, briefs, and other legal documents
          - 1948-1950, (5 folders)
          - 1951
            - Jan.-Feb., (2 folders)
            - Mar.-Dec., (4 folders) (Box 296)
          - 1952-1954, undated, (4 folders)
      - Young Communist League, 1949-1950
    - United Auto Workers, 1955-1977
  - Miscellany (Box 297)
    - Awards and honors
      - Four Freedoms Award, 1983, 1991-1992
      - Miscellaneous, 1967-1972, 1984-1992, (3 folders)
      - Presidential Medal of Freedom, 1992, (2 folders)
    - Biographical file, 1983, 1989-1992
    - Cincinnati Planning Commission controversy about Communist Party affiliations, 1953
    - Crawford, Joan, 1974
    - Death of Rauh
      - General, 1992-1993, (4 folders)
      - Scrapbook, 1992, (3 folders) (Box 298)
    - District of Columbia School of Law, 1991-1998, (2 folders)
    - Family papers
      - Birth certificate and health certifications, 1913-1929, 1945-1948
      - Correspondence, 1974-1980, 1989, 2008
      - Newspaper clippings, 1966-1973
      - Poetry, 1961, undated
    - Finley, Joe, 1981
    - Harvard University, Cambridge, Mass., 1930-1931, undated
    - Library of Congress, 1994-1995, circa 2008
    - Oral history interview with Rauh, 1992
    - Photographs, 1972-1985, undated, (4 folders)
    - Press and magazine articles about Rauh
      - 1951-1965, (2 folders)
      - 1966-1996, undated, (9 folders) (Box 299)
    - Printed matter, 1935, 1968-1975, 1988-1990, undated
    - Speeches
      - By Rauh
        - 1971-1989, (9 folders)
        - 1990
          - Feb.
          - Mar.-Dec. (Box 300)
        - 1991-1992, (4 folders)
      - By others, 1990
    - Writings
      - By Rauh
        - Articles, 1957-1961, 1970-1993, (5 folders)
        - Book reviews, 1976, 1983
      - By others, 1961, 1969-1975, 1989-1990, (3 folders)
- Restricted: Part I: Legal File, 1969 (Box R301)
  A restricted item.
  Described according to the part, series, and container from which it was removed.
  - Part I: Legal File (Box R301)
    - United Auto Workers, AFL/CIO
      - Mields, Jennifer Robin, 1969 (Container 110)